<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Temporal and Spatio-Temporal Modeling and Monitoring of Epidemic
		Phenomena // Implementation of statistical methods for the
		modeling and change-point detection in time series of counts,
		proportions and categorical data, as well as for the modeling
		of continuous-time epidemic phenomena, e.g., discrete-space
		setups such as the spatially enriched Susceptible-Exposed-
		Infectious-Recovered (SEIR) models, or continuous-space point
		process data such as the occurrence of infectious diseases.
		Main focus is on outbreak detection in count data time series
		originating from public health surveillance of communicable
		diseases, but applications could just as well originate from
		environmetrics, reliability engineering, econometrics or social
		sciences. Currently, the package contains implementations of
		many typical outbreak detection procedures such as Farrington
		et al (1996), Noufaily et al (2012) or the negative binomial
		LR-CUSUM method described in Hhle and Paul (2008). A novel
		CUSUM approach combining logistic and multinomial logistic
		modelling is also included. Furthermore, inference methods for
		the retrospective infectious disease models in Held et al
		(2005), Held et al (2006), Paul et al (2008), Paul and Held
		(2011), Held and Paul (2012), and Meyer and Held (2014) are
		provided. Continuous self-exciting spatio-temporal point
		processes are modeled through additive-multiplicative
		conditional intensities as described in Hhle (2009) ('twinSIR',
		discrete space) and Meyer et al (2012) ('twinstim', continuous
		space). The package contains several real-world data sets, the
		ability to simulate outbreak data, visualize the results of the
		monitoring in temporal, spatial or spatio-temporal fashion.
		Note: Using the 'boda' algorithm requires the 'INLA' package,
		which should be installed automatically through the specified
		Additional_repositories, if uninstalled dependencies are also
		requested. As this might not work under OS X it might be
		necessary to manually install the 'INLA' package as specified
		at http://www.r-inla.org/download.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
