<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Automatic Scoring of the Cognitive Reflection Test // A tool for
		researchers and psychologists to automatically code open-ended
		responses to the Cognitive Reflection Test (CRT), a widely used
		class of tests in cognitive science and psychology for
		assessing an individual's propensity to override an incorrect
		gut response and engage in further reflection to find a correct
		answer. This package facilitates the standardization of
		Cognitive Reflection Test responses analysis across large
		datasets in cognitive psychology, decision-making, and related
		fields. By automating the coding process, it not only reduces
		manual effort but also aims to reduce the variability
		introduced by subjective interpretation of open-ended
		responses, contributing to a more consistent and reliable
		analysis. 'reflectR' supports automatic coding and machine
		scoring for the original English-language version of CRT
		(Frederick, 2005) doi:10.1257/089533005775196732, as well as
		for CRT4 and CRT7, 4- and 7-item versions, respectively (Toplak
		et al., 2014) doi:10.1080/13546783.2013.844729, for the CRT-
		long version built via Item Response Theory by Primi and
		colleagues (2016) doi:10.1002/bdm.1883, and for CRT-2 by
		Thomson  Oppenheimer (2016) doi:10.1017/s1930297500007622.
		Note: While 'reflectR' draws inspiration from the principles
		and scientific literature underlying the different versions of
		the Cognitive Reflection Test, it has been independently
		developed and does not hold any affiliation with any of the
		original authors. The development of this package benefited
		significantly from the kind insight and suggestion provided by
		Dr. Keela Thomson, whose contribution is gratefully
		acknowledged. Additional gratitude is extended to Dr. Paolo
		Giovanni Cicirelli, Prof. Marinella Paciello, Dr. Carmela
		Sportelli, and Prof. Francesca D'Errico, who not only
		contributed to the manual multi-rater coding of CRT-2 items but
		also profoundly influenced the understanding of the importance
		and practical relevance of cognitive reflection within
		personality, social, and cognitive psychology research.
		Acknowledgment is also due to the European project STERHEOTYPES
		(STudying European Racial Hoaxes and sterEOTYPES) for funding
		the data collection that produced the datasets initially used
		for manual multi-rater coding of CRT-2 items.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
