<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Estimating birth and death rates based on phylogenies // (i) For
		a given species phylogeny on present day data which is
		calibrated to calendar-time, a method for estimating maximum
		likelihood speciation and extinction processes is provided. The
		method allows for non-constant rates. Rates may change (1) as a
		function of time, i.e. rate shifts at specified times or mass
		extinction events (likelihood implemented as LikShifts,
		optimization as bd.shifts.optim and visualized as
		bd.shifts.plot) or (2) as a function of the number of species,
		i.e. density-dependence (likelihood implemented as LikDD and
		optimization as bd.densdep.optim) or (3) extinction rate may be
		a function of species age (likelihood implemented as LikAge and
		optimization as bd.age.optim.matlab). Note that the methods
		take into account the whole phylogeny, in particular it
		accounts for the "pull of the present" effect. (1-3) can take
		into account incomplete species sampling, as long as each
		species has the same probability of being sampled. For a given
		phylogeny on higher taxa (i.e. all but one species per taxa are
		missing), where the number of species is known within each
		higher taxa, speciation and extinction rates can be estimated
		under model (1) (implemented within LikShifts and
		bd.shifts.optim with groups !=0). (ii) For a given phylogeny
		with sequentially sampled tips, e.g. a virus phylogeny, rates
		can be estimated under a model where rates vary across time
		using bdsky.stt.optim based on likelihood LikShiftsSTT
		(extending LikShifts and bd.shifts.optim). Furthermore, rates
		may vary as a function of host types using LikTypesSTT
		(multitype branching process extending functions in R package
		diversitree). This function can furthermore calculate the
		likelihood under an epidemiological model where infected
		individuals are first exposed and then infectious.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
