<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Mixed Level Response Surface Designs // Response Surface Designs
		(RSDs) involving factors not all at same levels are called
		Mixed Level RSDs (or Asymmetric RSDs). In many practical
		situations, RSDs with asymmetric levels will be more suitable
		as it explores more regions in the design space. (J.S. Mehta
		and M.N. Das (1968) doi:10.2307/1267046. "Asymmetric rotatable
		designs and orthogonal transformations").This package contains
		function named ATORDs_I()  for generating asymmetric third
		order rotatable designs (ATORDs) based on third order designs
		given by Das and Narasimham (1962). Function ATORDs_II()
		generates asymmetric third order rotatable designs developed
		using t-design of unequal set sizes, which are smaller in size
		as compared to design generated by function ATORDs_I(). In
		general, third order rotatable designs can be classified into
		two classes viz., designs that are suitable for sequential
		experimentation and designs for non-sequential experimentation.
		The sequential experimentation approach involves conducting the
		trials step by step whereas, in the non-sequential
		experimentation approach, the entire runs are executed in one
		go (M. N. Das and V. Narasimham (1962)
		doi:10.1214/AOMS/1177704374. "Construction of Rotatable Designs
		through Balanced Incomplete Block Designs").  ATORDs_I() and
		ATORDs_II() functions generate non-sequential asymmetric third
		order designs. Function named SeqTORD() generates symmetric
		sequential third order design in blocks and also gives
		G-efficiency of the given design. Function named Asymseq()
		generates asymmetric sequential third order designs in blocks
		(M. Hemavathi, Eldho Varghese, Shashi Shekhar and Seema Jaggi
		(2020) doi:10.1080/02664763.2020.1864817. "Sequential
		asymmetric third order rotatable designs (SATORDs)"). In
		response surface design, situations may arise in which some of
		the factors are qualitative in nature (Jyoti Divecha and Bharat
		Tarapara (2017) doi:10.1080/08982112.2016.1217338. "Small,
		balanced, efficient, optimal, and near rotatable response
		surface designs for factorial experiments asymmetrical in some
		quantitative, qualitative factors").  The Function named
		QualRSD() generates second order design with qualitative
		factors along with their D-efficiency and G-efficiency.  The
		function named RotatabilityQ() calculates a measure of
		rotatability (measure Q, 0 = Q = 1) given by Draper and
		Pukelshiem(1990) for given a design based on a second order
		model, (Norman R. Draper and Friedrich Pukelsheim(1990)
		doi:10.1080/00401706.1990.10484635. "Another look at
		rotatability").
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
