<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Computation of BRINDA Adjusted Micronutrient Biomarkers for
		Inflammation // Inflammation can affect many micronutrient
		biomarkers and can thus lead to incorrect diagnosis of
		individuals and to over- or under-estimate the prevalence of
		deficiency in a population. Biomarkers Reflecting Inflammation
		and Nutritional Determinants of Anemia (BRINDA) is a multi-
		agency and multi-country partnership designed to improve the
		interpretation of nutrient biomarkers in settings of
		inflammation and to generate context-specific estimates of risk
		factors for anemia (Suchdev (2016) doi:10.3945/an.115.010215).
		In the past few years, BRINDA published a series of papers to
		provide guidance on how to adjust micronutrient biomarkers,
		retinol binding protein, serum retinol, serum ferritin by
		Namaste (2020), soluble transferrin receptor (sTfR), serum
		zinc, serum and Red Blood Cell (RBC) folate, and serum B-12,
		using inflammation markers, alpha-1-acid glycoprotein (AGP)
		and/or C-Reactive Protein (CRP) by Namaste (2020)
		doi:10.1093/ajcn/nqaa141, Rohner (2017)
		doi:10.3945/ajcn.116.142232, McDonald (2020)
		doi:10.1093/ajcn/nqz304, and Young (2020)
		doi:10.1093/ajcn/nqz303. The BRINDA inflammation adjustment
		method mainly focuses on Women of Reproductive Age (WRA) and
		Preschool-age Children (PSC); however, the general principle of
		the BRINDA method might apply to other population groups. The
		BRINDA R package is a user-friendly all-in-one R package that
		uses a series of functions to implement BRINDA adjustment
		method, as described above. The BRINDA R package will first
		carry out rigorous checks and provides users guidance to
		correct data or input errors (if they occur) prior to
		inflammation adjustments. After no errors are detected, the
		package implements the BRINDA inflammation adjustment for up to
		five micronutrient biomarkers, namely retinol-binding-protein,
		serum retinol, serum ferritin, sTfR, and serum zinc (when
		appropriate), using inflammation indicators of AGP and/or CRP
		for various population groups. Of note, adjustment for serum
		and RBC folate and serum B-12 is not included in the R package,
		since evidence shows that no adjustment is needed for these
		micronutrient biomarkers in either WRA or PSC groups (Young
		(2020) doi:10.1093/ajcn/nqz303).
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
