<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		A Metapackage for Asian Countries RESTful APIs and Curated
		Datasets // A metapackage that brings together a comprehensive
		collection of R packages providing access to APIs functions and
		curated datasets from China, Japan, South Korea, India, and
		Indonesia. It includes real-time and historical data through
		public RESTful APIs (Nager.Date, World Bank API, REST Countries
		API) and extensive curated collections of open datasets
		covering economics, demographics, public health, environmental
		data, natural disasters, political indicators, and social
		metrics. Designed to provide researchers, analysts, educators,
		and data scientists with centralized access to Asian data
		sources, this metapackage facilitates reproducible research,
		comparative analysis, and teaching applications focused on
		these five major Asian countries. Included packages: -
		'ChinAPIs': APIs functions and curated datasets for China and
		Hong Kong covering air quality, demographics, input-output
		tables, epidemiology, political structure, and social
		indicators. - 'JapanAPIs': APIs functions and curated datasets
		for Japan including natural disasters, economic production,
		vehicle industry, air quality, demographics, and administrative
		divisions. - 'SouthKoreAPIs': APIs functions and curated
		datasets for South Korea covering public health outbreaks,
		social surveys, elections, economic indicators, natural
		disasters, climate data, energy consumption, cultural
		information, and financial markets. - 'IndiAPIs': APIs
		functions and curated datasets for India with comprehensive
		collections and real-time access to economic, demographic, and
		geopolitical indicators. - 'IndonesiAPIs': APIs functions and
		curated datasets for Indonesia covering holidays, economic
		indicators, consumer prices, poverty probability, food prices
		by region, tourism destinations, and minimum wage statistics.
		For more information on the APIs, see: 'Nager.Date'
		https://date.nager.at/Api, 'World Bank API' https://datahelpdes
		k.worldbank.org/knowledgebase/articles/889392, and 'REST
		Countries API' https://restcountries.com/.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
