<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		General Copula Theory and Many Utility Functions // Extensive
		functions for copula computations and related mathematical
		operations are given that are oriented around the oft cited and
		fundamental copula theory described by Nelsen (2006), Joe
		(2015), and other selected works. The lower, upper, product,
		and select other copulas are implemented. Individual copula
		functional support is intentionally limited to keep the package
		focused on an API to general copula theory. Expressions
		available for an arbitrary copula include the diagonal of a
		copula, the survival copula, the dual of a copula, co-copula,
		and numerical copula density. Level curves (sets) are
		available. Horizontal and vertical copula sections and
		derivatives of such sections also are supported. The numerical
		derivatives of a copula are provided as well as inverses;
		functions for copula simulation thus are supported. Composition
		of copulas is provided: (1) composition of a single copula
		using two composition parameters, (2) composition of two
		copulas using two composition parameters, (3) composition of
		two copulas using four composition parameters, and (4) random
		variates of composited copulas.  Characteristics of copulas
		include Kendall Tau, Spearman Rho, Gini Gamma, Blomqvist Beta,
		and Schweizer-Wolff Sigma, tail dependency, and tail order.
		Logical evaluators of positively/negatively quadrant
		dependency, left-tail decreasing, and right-tail increasing
		also are available. The Kullback-Leibler divergence and Vuong's
		Procedure to support inference are available. Quantile and
		median regression for V with respect to U and U with respect to
		V is available. Empirical copulas (EC) are supported. ECs are
		dependent on gridded data structures for which generation
		capability is provided. The derivatives of the EC grid are
		computable. Also, the inverses of the derivatives, which are
		the conditional QDFs of copula sections also are computable.
		Median and quantile regression of an EC also is supported along
		with support for EC simulation of V conditional on U.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
