<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Automated Visualization of Statistical Tests // Visualization of
		the most powerful statistical hypothesis test. The function
		vistat() visualizes the statistical hypothesis testing between
		the dependent variable (response) varsample and the independent
		variable (feature) varfactor. The statistical hypothesis test
		(including the eventual corresponding post-hoc analysis) with
		the highest statistical power fulfilling the assumptions of the
		corresponding test is chosen based on a decision tree. A graph
		displaying the raw data accordingly to the chosen test is
		generated, the test statistics including eventual post-hoc-
		analysis are returned. The automated workflow is especially
		suited for browser based interfaces to server-based deployments
		of R. Implemented tests: lm(), t.test(), wilcox.test(), aov(),
		kruskal.test(), fisher.test(), chisqu.test(). Implemented tests
		to check the normal distribution of standardized residuals:
		shapiro.test() and ad.test(). Implemented post-hoc tests:
		TukeyHSD() for aov() and pairwise.wilcox.test() for
		kruskal.test(). For the comparison of averages, the following
		algorithm is implemented: If the p-values of the standardized
		residuals of both shapiro.test() or ad.test() are smaller than
		1-conf.level, kruskal.test() resp. wilcox.test() are performed,
		otherwise the oneway.test() and aov() resp. t.test() are
		performed and displayed. Exception: If the sample size is
		bigger than 100, t.test() is always performed and wilcox.test()
		is never executed (Lumley et al. (2002)
		doi:10.1146/annurev.publhealth.23.100901.140546). For the test
		of independence of count data, Cochran's rule (Cochran (1954)
		doi:10.2307/3001666) is implemented: If more than 20 percent of
		all cells have a count smaller than 5, fisher.test() is
		performed and displayed, otherwise chisqu.test(). In both cases
		case an additional mosaic plot is generated.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
