<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Accident and Development Period Adjusted Linear Pools for
		Actuarial Stochastic Reserving // Loss reserving generally
		focuses on identifying a single model that can generate
		superior predictive performance. However, different loss
		reserving models specialise in capturing different aspects of
		loss data. This is recognised in practice in the sense that
		results from different models are often considered, and
		sometimes combined. For instance, actuaries may take a weighted
		average of the prediction outcomes from various loss reserving
		models, often based on subjective assessments. This package
		allows for the use of a systematic framework to objectively
		combine (i.e. ensemble) multiple stochastic loss reserving
		models such that the strengths offered by different models can
		be utilised effectively. Our framework is developed in Avanzi
		et al. (2023). Firstly, our criteria model combination
		considers the full distributional properties of the ensemble
		and not just the central estimate - which is of particular
		importance in the reserving context. Secondly, our framework is
		that it is tailored for the features inherent to reserving
		data. These include, for instance, accident, development,
		calendar, and claim maturity effects. Crucially, the relative
		importance and scarcity of data across accident periods renders
		the problem distinct from the traditional ensemble techniques
		in statistical learning. Our framework is illustrated with a
		complex synthetic dataset. In the results, the optimised
		ensemble outperforms both (i) traditional model selection
		strategies, and (ii) an equally weighted ensemble. In
		particular, the improvement occurs not only with central
		estimates but also relevant quantiles, such as the 75th
		percentile of reserves (typically of interest to both insurers
		and regulators). Reference: Avanzi B, Li Y, Wong B, Xian A
		(2023) "Ensemble distributional forecasting for insurance loss
		reserving" doi:10.48550/arXiv.2206.08541.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
