<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Checks Title, Abstract and Keywords to Optimise Discoverability
		// A suite of tools are provided here to support authors in
		making their research more discoverable. check_keywords() -
		this function checks the keywords to assess whether they are
		already represented in the title and abstract. check_fields() -
		this function compares terminology used across the title,
		abstract and keywords to assess where terminological diversity
		(i.e. the use of synonyms) could increase the likelihood of the
		record being identified in a search. The function looks for
		terms in the title and abstract that also exist in other fields
		and highlights these as needing attention. suggest_keywords() -
		this function takes a full text document and produces a list of
		unigrams, bigrams and trigrams (1-, 2- or 2-word phrases)
		present in the full text after removing stop words (words with
		a low utility in natural language processing) that do not occur
		in the title or abstract that may be suitable candidates for
		keywords. suggest_title() - this function takes a full text
		document and produces a list of the most frequently used
		unigrams, bigrams and trigrams after removing stop words that
		do not occur in the abstract or keywords that may be suitable
		candidates for title words. check_title() - this function
		carries out a number of sub tasks:  1) it compares the length
		(number of words) of the title with the mean length of titles
		in major bibliographic databases to assess whether the title is
		likely to be too short; 2) it assesses the proportion of stop
		words in the title to highlight titles with low utility in
		search engines that strip out stop words; 3) it compares the
		title with a given sample of record titles from an .ris import
		and calculates a similarity score based on phrase overlap. This
		highlights the level of uniqueness of the title. This version
		of the package also contains functions currently in a non-CRAN
		package called 'litsearchr'
		https://github.com/elizagrames/litsearchr.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
