<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		L-Moments, Censored L-Moments, Trimmed L-Moments, L-Comoments,
		and Many Distributions // Extensive functions for the theory of
		L-moments (LMs) in addition to probability-weighted moments
		(PWMs), and parameter (p) estimation for numerous familiar and
		not-so-familiar distributions. Estimation of LMs for the same
		distributions is provided as are L-moment ratio diagrams.
		Estimation of LMs for right-tail and left-tail censoring by
		known or unknown threshold and also by indicator variable is
		available. Asymmetric trimmed LMs (TL-moments, TLMs) are
		supported as are numerical integrations to dynamically compute
		trajectories of select TLM ratios for TL-moment ratio diagram
		construction.  LMs of residual (resid.) and reversed (rev.)
		resid. life are implemented along with 13 operators on quantile
		functions that are useful in reliability, lifetime, and
		survival analysis.  Exact analytical bootstrap estimates of
		order statistics, LMs, and variances-covariances of LMs are
		provided. The Harri-Coble Tau34-squared Test for Normality is
		available. Distribution support with "L" (LMs), "TL" (TLMs) and
		added (+) support for right-tail censoring (RC) encompasses:
		Asymmetric (Asy.) Exponential (Exp.) Power [L], Asy. Triangular
		[L], Cauchy [TL], Eta-Mu [L], Exp. [L], Gamma [L], Generalized
		(Gen.) Exp. Poisson [L], Gen. Extreme Value [L], Gen. Lambda
		[L,TL], Gen. Logistic [L), Gen. Normal [L], Gen. Pareto [L+RC,
		TL], Govindarajulu [L], Gumbel [L], Kappa [L], Kappa-Mu [L],
		Kumaraswamy [L], Laplace [L], Linear Mean Residual Quantile
		Function [L], Normal [L], 3-p log-Normal [L], Pearson Type III
		[L], Rayleigh [L], Rev. Gumbel [L+RC], Rice/Rician (L), Slash
		[TL], 3-p Student t [L], Truncated Exponential [L], Wakeby [L],
		and Weibull [L]. LMs have multivariate analogs; the sample
		L-comoments (LCMs) are implemented and might have considerable
		application with copulas because LCMs measure asymmetric
		association and higher comoments or comovements of variables.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
