<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Relaxed Lasso Model for Data Which Might Have Long Run Times
		Using 'glmnet' // For some datasets, for example when the
		design matrix is not of full rank, 'glmnet' may have very long
		run times when fitting the relaxed lasso model, in particular
		when fitting a Cox based model, making it difficult to get
		solutions either from glmnet() or cv.glmnet().  In this
		package, 'glmnetr', we provide a workaround and solve for the
		non penalized relaxed model where gamma=0 for model structures
		analogue to R functions like glm() or coxph() of the survival
		package.  If you are not fitting relaxed lasso models, or if
		you are able to get convergence using 'glmnet', then this
		package may not be of much benefit to you.  Note, while this
		package may allow one to fit relaxed lasso models that have
		difficulties converging using 'glmnet', this package does not
		afford the full function and versatility of 'glmnet'. In
		addition to fitting the relaxed lasso model this package also
		includes the function cv.glmnetr() to perform a cross
		validation to identify hyper-parameters for a lasso fit, much
		like the cv.glmnet() function of the 'glmnet' package.
		Additionally, the package includes the function
		nested.glmnetr() to perform a nested cross validation to assess
		the fit of a cross validated derived lasso model fit.  If
		though you are fitting not a relaxed lasso model but an
		elastic-net model, then the R-packages 'nestedcv'
		https://cran.r-project.org/package=nestedcv, 'glmnetSE'
		https://cran.r-project.org/package=glmnetSE or others may
		provide greater functionality when performing a nested CV. As
		with the 'glmnet' package, this package passes most relevant
		output to the output object and tabular and graphical summaries
		can be generated using the summary and plot functions.  Use of
		the 'glmnetr' has many similarities to the 'glmnet' package and
		it is recommended that the user of 'glmnetr' first become
		familiar with the 'glmnet' package
		https://cran.r-project.org/package=glmnet, with the "An
		Introduction to 'glmnet'" and "The Relaxed Lasso" being
		especially helpful in this regard.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
