<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Analysis of Data Acquired Using the Receiver Operating
		Characteristic Paradigm and Its Extensions // A common task in
		medical imaging is assessing whether a new imaging system or
		device is an improvement over an existing one. Observer
		performance methodology, such as receiver operating
		characteristic analysis, is widely used for this purpose.
		Receiver operating characteristic studies are often required
		for regulatory approval of new devices. The purpose of this
		work is to software for the analysis of data acquired using the
		receiver operating characteristic paradigm and its location
		specific extensions. It is an enhanced implementation of
		existing Windows software (http://www.devchakraborty.com). In
		this paradigm the radiologist rates each image for confidence
		in presence of disease. The images are typically split equally
		between actually non-diseased and diseased. A common figure of
		merit is the area under the receiver operating characteristic
		curve, which has the physical interpretation as the probability
		that a diseased image is rated higher than a non-diseased one.
		In receiver operating characteristic studies a number of
		radiologists (readers) rate images in two or more treatments,
		and the object of the analysis is to determine the significance
		of the inter-treatment difference between reader-averaged
		figures of merit. In the free-response paradigm the reader
		marks the locations of suspicious regions and rates each region
		for confidence in presence of disease, and credit for detection
		is only given if a true lesion is correctly localized. In the
		region of interest paradigm each image is divided into a number
		of regions and the reader rates each region. Each paradigm
		requires definition of a valid figure of merit that rewards
		correct decisions and penalizes incorrect ones and specialized
		significance testing procedures are applied. The package reads
		data in all currently used data formats including Excel.
		Significance testing uses two models in widespread use, a
		jackknife pseudo-value based model and an analysis of variance
		model with correlated errors. Included are tools for (1)
		calculating a variety of free-response figures of merit; (2)
		sample size estimation for planning a future study based on
		pilot data; (3) viewing empirical operating characteristics in
		receiver operating characteristic and free-response paradigms;
		(4) producing formatted report files; and (5) saving a data
		file in appropriate format for analysis with alternate
		software. In addition to open-source access to the functions,
		the package includes a graphical interface for users already
		familiar with the Windows software, who simply wish to run the
		program.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
