<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Variance Component Analysis // ANOVA-type estimation (prediction)
		of random effects in linear mixed models is implemented,
		following Searle et al. (1991, ANOVA for unbalanced data). For
		better performance the SWEEP-Operator is implemented for
		generating the ANOVA Type-1 error sum of squares. Restricted
		Maximum Likelihood (REML) estimation is also available making
		use of the 'lme4' package. The primary objective of this
		package is to perform Variance Component Analyses (VCA). This
		is a special type of analysis frequently used in verifying the
		precision performance of diagnostics. The Satterthwaite
		approximation of the total degrees of freedom and for
		individual variance components is implemented for models fitted
		by ANOVA as well as for models fitted by REML. These are used
		in the Chi-Squared tests against a claimed value, and in the
		respective confidence intervals. Satterthwaite's approximation
		of denominator degrees of freedom in t-/F-tests of fixed
		effects are also available. For models fitted by (REML) the
		variance-covariance matrix of the variance components is
		approximated by the method pointed out in Giesbrecht  Burns
		(1985), which is required for applying the Satterthwaite
		approximation of the degrees of freedom. For models fitted by
		ANOVA the method pointed out in Searle et al. (1991) employing
		quadratic forms generating ANOVA sum of squares is also
		available. There are several functions for extracting, random
		effects, fixed effects, variance-covariance matrices of random
		and fixed effects. Residuals (marginal, conditional) can be
		extracted as raw, standardized and studentized residuals.
		Additionally, plotting methods for residuals and random effects
		and a variability chart are available. The latter is useful for
		visualizing the variability in sub-classes emerging from the
		experimental design.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
