<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Descriptive Univariate Statistics // It generates summary
		statistics on the input dataset using different descriptive
		univariate statistical measures on entire data or at a group
		level. Though there are other packages which does similar job
		but each of these are deficient in one form or other, in the
		measures generated, in treating numeric, character and date
		variables alike, no functionality to view these measures on a
		group level or the way the output is represented. Given the
		foremost role of the descriptive statistics in any of the
		exploratory data analysis or solution development, there is a
		need for a more constructive, structured and refined version
		over these packages. This is the idea behind the package and it
		brings together all the required descriptive measures to give
		an initial understanding of the data quality, distribution in a
		faster,easier and elaborative way.The function brings an
		additional capability to be able to generate these statistical
		measures on the entire dataset or at a group level. It
		calculates measures of central tendency (mean, median),
		distribution (count, proportion), dispersion (min, max,
		quantile, standard deviation, variance) and shape (skewness,
		kurtosis). Addition to these measures, it provides information
		on the data type, count on no. of rows, unique entries and
		percentage of missing entries. More importantly the measures
		are generated based on the data types as required by
		them,rather than applying numerical measures on character and
		data variables and vice versa. Output as a dataframe object
		gives a very neat representation, which often is useful when
		working with a large number of columns. It can easily be
		exported as csv and analyzed further or presented as a summary
		report for the data.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
