<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Functional Regression for Irregularly Timed Data // Performs
		functional regression, and some related approaches, for
		intensive longitudinal data (see the book by Walls  Schafer,
		2006, Models for Intensive Longitudinal Data, Oxford) when such
		data is not necessarily observed on an equally spaced grid of
		times.  The approach generally follows the ideas of Goldsmith,
		Bobb, Crainiceanu, Caffo, and Reich
		(2011)DOI:10.1198/jcgs.2010.10007 and the approach taken in
		their sample code, but with some modifications to make it more
		feasible to use with long rather than wide, non-rectangular
		longitudinal datasets with unequal and potentially random
		measurement times.  It also allows easy plotting of the
		correlation between the smoothed covariate and the outcome as a
		function of time, which can add additional insights on how to
		interpret a functional regression.  Additionally, it also
		provides several permutation tests for the significance of the
		functional predictor.  The heuristic interpretation of ``time''
		is used to describe the index of the functional predictor, but
		the same methods can equally be used for another unidimensional
		continuous index, such as space along a north-south axis.  Note
		that most of the functionality of this package has been
		superseded by added features after 2016 in the 'pfr' function
		by Jonathan Gellar, Mathew W. McLean, Jeff Goldsmith, and
		Fabian Scheipl, in the 'refund' package built by Jeff Goldsmith
		and co-authors and maintained by Julia Wrobel. The development
		of the funreg package in 2015 and 2016 was part of a research
		project supported by Award R03 CA171809-01 from the National
		Cancer Institute and Award P50 DA010075 from the National
		Institute on Drug Abuse. The content is solely the
		responsibility of the authors and does not necessarily
		represent the official views of the National Institute on Drug
		Abuse, the National Cancer Institute, or the National
		Institutes of Health.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
