<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Latin American Data via 'RESTful' APIs and Curated Datasets //
		Brings together a comprehensive collection of R packages
		providing access to API functions and curated datasets from
		Argentina, Brazil, Chile, Colombia, and Peru. Includes real-
		time and historical data through public 'RESTful' APIs
		('Nager.Date', World Bank API, REST Countries API, and country-
		specific APIs) and extensive curated collections of open
		datasets covering economics, demographics, public health,
		environmental data, political indicators, social metrics, and
		cultural information. Designed to provide researchers,
		analysts, educators, and data scientists with centralized
		access to Latin American data sources, facilitating
		reproducible research, comparative analysis, and teaching
		applications focused on these five major Latin American
		countries. Included packages: - 'ArgentinAPI': API functions
		and curated datasets for Argentina covering exchange rates,
		inflation, political figures, national holidays and more. -
		'BrazilDataAPI': API functions and curated datasets for Brazil
		covering postal codes, banks, economic indicators, holidays,
		company registrations and more. - 'ChileDataAPI': API functions
		and curated datasets for Chile covering financial indicators
		('UF', UTM, Dollar, Euro, Yen, Copper, Bitcoin, 'IPSA' index),
		holidays and more. - 'ColombiAPI': API functions and curated
		datasets for Colombia covering geographic locations, cultural
		attractions, economic indicators, demographic data, national
		holidays and more. - 'PeruAPIs': API functions and curated
		datasets for Peru covering economic indicators, demographics,
		national holidays, administrative divisions, electoral data,
		biodiversity and more. For more information on the APIs, see:
		'Nager.Date' https://date.nager.at/Api, World Bank API https://
		datahelpdesk.worldbank.org/knowledgebase/articles/889392, REST
		Countries API https://restcountries.com/, 'ArgentinaDatos' API
		https://argentinadatos.com/, 'BrasilAPI'
		https://brasilapi.com.br/, 'FINDIC' https://findic.cl/, and
		API-Colombia https://api-colombia.com/.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
