<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		QTL EM Algorithm Mapping and Hotspots Detection // For QTL
		mapping, this package comprises several functions designed to
		execute diverse tasks, such as simulating or analyzing data,
		calculating significance thresholds, and visualizing QTL
		mapping results. The single-QTL or multiple-QTL method, which
		enables the fitting and comparison of various statistical
		models, is employed to analyze the data for estimating QTL
		parameters. The models encompass linear regression, permutation
		tests, normal mixture models, and truncated normal mixture
		models. The Gaussian stochastic process is utilized to compute
		significance thresholds for QTL detection on a genetic linkage
		map within experimental populations. Two types of data,
		complete genotyping, and selective genotyping data from various
		experimental populations, including backcross, F2, recombinant
		inbred (RI) populations, and advanced intercrossed (AI)
		populations, are considered in the QTL mapping analysis. For
		QTL hotspot detection, statistical methods can be developed
		based on either utilizing individual-level data or summarized
		data. We have proposed a statistical framework capable of
		handling both individual-level data and summarized QTL data for
		QTL hotspot detection. Our statistical framework can overcome
		the underestimation of thresholds resulting from ignoring the
		correlation structure among traits. Additionally, it can
		identify different types of hotspots with minimal computational
		cost during the detection process. Here, we endeavor to furnish
		the R codes for our QTL mapping and hotspot detection methods,
		intended for general use in genes, genomics, and genetics
		studies. The QTL mapping methods for the complete and selective
		genotyping designs are based on the multiple interval mapping
		(MIM) model proposed by Kao, C.-H. , Z.-B. Zeng and R. D.
		Teasdale (1999) doi: 10.1534/genetics.103.021642 and H.-I Lee,
		H.-A. Ho and C.-H. Kao (2014) doi: 10.1534/genetics.114.168385,
		respectively. The QTL hotspot detection analysis is based on
		the method by Wu, P.-Y., M.-.H. Yang, and C.-H. Kao (2021) doi:
		10.1093/g3journal/jkab056.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
