<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Parentage Assignment using Bi-Allelic Genetic Markers // Can be
		used for paternity and maternity assignment and outperforms
		conventional methods where closely related individuals occur in
		the pool of possible parents. The method compares the genotypes
		of offspring with any combination of potentials parents and
		scores the number of mismatches of these individuals at bi-
		allelic genetic markers (e.g. Single Nucleotide Polymorphisms).
		It elaborates on a prior exclusion method based on the
		Homozygous Opposite Test (HOT; Huisman 2017
		doi:10.1111/1755-0998.12665) by introducing the additional
		exclusion criterion HIPHOP (Homozygous Identical Parents,
		Heterozygous Offspring are Precluded; Cockburn et al., in
		revision). Potential parents are excluded if they have more
		mismatches than can be expected due to genotyping error and
		mutation, and thereby one can identify the true genetic parents
		and detect situations where one (or both) of the true parents
		is not sampled. Package 'hiphop' can deal with (a) the case
		where there is contextual information about parentage of the
		mother (i.e. a female has been seen to be involved in
		reproductive tasks such as nest building), but paternity is
		unknown (e.g. due to promiscuity), (b) where both parents need
		to be assigned, because there is no contextual information on
		which female laid eggs and which male fertilized them (e.g.
		polygynandrous mating system where multiple females and males
		deposit young in a common nest, or organisms with external
		fertilisation that breed in aggregations). For details:
		Cockburn, A., Penalba, J.V.,Jaccoud, D.,Kilian, A., Brouwer,
		L., Double, M.C., Margraf, N., Osmond, H.L., van de Pol, M. and
		Kruuk, L.E.B. (in revision). HIPHOP: improved paternity
		assignment among close relatives using a simple exclusion
		method for bi-allelic markers. Molecular Ecology Resources, DOI
		to be added upon acceptance.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
