<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Design of the Best Phage Cocktail // There are 4 possible
		methods: "ExhaustiveSearch"; "ExhaustivePhi";
		"ClusteringSearch"; and "ClusteringPhi". "ExhaustiveSearch"--
		gives you the best phage cocktail from a phage-bacteria
		infection network. It checks different phage cocktail sizes
		from 1 to 7 and only stops before if it lyses all bacteria.
		Other option is when users have decided not to obtain a phage
		cocktail size higher than a limit value. "ExhaustivePhi"--
		firstly, it finds Phi out. Phi is a formula indicating the
		necessary phage cocktail size. Phi needs nestedness temperature
		and fill, which are internally calculated. This function will
		only look for the best combination (phage cocktail) with a Phi
		size. "ClusteringSearch"-- firstly, an agglomerative
		hierarchical clustering using Ward's algorithm is calculated
		for phages. They will be clustered according to bacteria lysed
		by them. PhageCocktail() chooses how many clusters are needed
		in order to select 1 phage per cluster. Using the phages
		selected during the clustering, it checks different phage
		cocktail sizes from 1 to 7 and only stops before if it lyses
		all bacteria. Other option is when users have decided not to
		obtain a phage cocktail size higher than a limit value.
		"ClusteringPhi"-- firstly, an agglomerative hierarchical
		clustering using Ward's algorithm is calculated for phages.
		They will be clustered according to bacteria lysed by them.
		PhageCocktail() chooses how many clusters are needed in order
		to select 1 phage per cluster. Once the function has one phage
		per cluster, it calculates Phi. If the number of clusters is
		less than Phi number, it will be changed to obtain, as minimum,
		this quantity of candidates (phages). Then, it calculates the
		best combination of Phi phages using those selected during the
		clustering with Ward algorithm. If you use PhageCocktail,
		please cite it as: "PhageCocktail: An R Package to Design Phage
		Cocktails from Experimental Phage-Bacteria Infection Networks".
		Mara Victoria Daz-Galin, Miguel A. Vega-Rodrguez, Felipe
		Molina. Computer Methods and Programs in Biomedicine, 106865,
		Elsevier Ireland, Clare, Ireland, 2022, ISSN: 0169-2607.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
