<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Proteomics Data Analysis Functions // Data analysis of proteomics
		experiments by mass spectrometry is supported by this
		collection of functions mostly dedicated to the analysis of
		(bottom-up) quantitative (XIC) data. Fasta-formatted proteomes
		(eg from UniProt Consortium doi:10.1093/nar/gky1049) can be
		read with automatic parsing and multiple annotation types (like
		species origin, abbreviated gene names, etc) extracted. Initial
		results from multiple software for protein (and peptide)
		quantitation can be imported (to a common format): MaxQuant
		(Tyanova et al 2016 doi:10.1038/nprot.2016.136), Dia-NN
		(Demichev et al 2020 doi:10.1038/s41592-019-0638-x),
		Fragpipe(da Veiga et al 2020 doi:10.1038/s41592-020-0912-y),
		MassChroq (Valot et al 2011 doi:10.1002/pmic.201100120), OpenMS
		(Strauss et al 2021 doi:10.1038/nmeth.3959), ProteomeDiscoverer
		(Orsburn 2021 doi:10.3390/proteomes9010015), Proline (Bouyssie
		et al 2020 doi:10.1093/bioinformatics/btaa118), AlphaPept
		(preprint Strauss et al doi:10.1101/2021.07.23.453379) and
		Wombat-P (Bouyssie et al 2023
		doi:10.1021/acs.jproteome.3c00636. Meta-data provided by
		initial analysis software and/or in sdrf format can be
		integrated to the analysis. Quantitative proteomics
		measurements frequently contain multiple NA values, due to
		physical absence of given peptides in some samples, limitations
		in sensitivity or other reasons. Help is provided to inspect
		the data graphically to investigate the nature of NA-values via
		their respective replicate measurements and to help/confirm the
		choice of NA-replacement algorithms. Meta-data in sdrf-format
		(Perez-Riverol et al 2020 doi:10.1021/acs.jproteome.0c00376) or
		similar tabular formats can be imported and included. Missing
		values can be inspected and imputed based on the concept of NA-
		neighbours or other methods. Dedicated filtering and
		statistical testing using the framework of package 'limma'
		doi:10.18129/B9.bioc.limma can be run, enhanced by multiple
		rounds of NA-replacements to provide robustness towards rare
		stochastic events. Multi-species samples, as frequently used in
		benchmark-tests (eg Navarro et al 2016 doi:10.1038/nbt.3685,
		Ramus et al 2016 doi:10.1016/j.jprot.2015.11.011), can be run
		with special options considering such sub-groups during
		normalization and testing. Subsequently, ROC curves (Hand and
		Till 2001 doi:10.1023/A:1010920819831) can be constructed to
		compare multiple analysis approaches. As detailed example the
		data-set from Ramus et al 2016 doi:10.1016/j.jprot.2015.11.011)
		quantified by MaxQuant, ProteomeDiscoverer, and Proline is
		provided with a detailed analysis of heterologous spike-in
		proteins.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
