<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Computation of 3D Tree Imbalance // The main goal of the R
		package 'treeDbalance' is to provide functions for the
		computation of several measurements of 3D node imbalance and
		their respective 3D tree imbalance indices, as well as to
		introduce the new 'phylo3D' format for rooted 3D tree objects.
		Moreover, it encompasses an example dataset of 3D models of 63
		beans in 'phylo3D' format. Please note that this R package was
		developed alongside the project described in the manuscript
		'Measuring 3D tree imbalance of plant models using graph-
		theoretical approaches' by M. Fischer, S. Kersting, and L. Khn
		(2023) arXiv:2307.14537, which provides precise mathematical
		definitions of the measurements. Furthermore, the package
		contains several helpful functions, for example, some auxiliary
		functions for computing the ancestors, descendants, and depths
		of the nodes, which ensures that the computations can be done
		in linear time. Most functions of 'treeDbalance' require as
		input a rooted tree in the 'phylo3D' format, an extended
		'phylo' format (as introduced in the R package 'ape' 1.9 in
		November 2006). Such a 'phylo3D' object must have at least two
		new attributes next to those required by the 'phylo' format:
		'node.coord', the coordinates of the nodes, as well as
		'edge.weight', the literal weight or volume of the edges.
		Optional attributes are 'edge.diam', the diameter of the edges,
		and 'edge.length', the length of the edges. For visualization
		purposes one can also specify 'edge.type', which ranges from
		normal cylinder to bud to leaf, as well as 'edge.color' to
		change the color of the edge depiction. This project was
		supported by the joint research project DIG-IT! funded by the
		European Social Fund (ESF), reference: ESF/14-BM-A55-0017/19,
		and the Ministry of Education, Science and Culture of
		Mecklenburg-Western Pomerania, Germany, as well as by the the
		project ArtIGROW, which is a part of the WIR!-Alliance
		'ArtIFARM  Artificial Intelligence in Farming' funded by the
		German Federal Ministry of Education and Research (FKZ:
		03WIR4805).
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
