<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Estimation of Environmental Variables and Genetic Parameters //
		Performs analyzes and estimates of environmental covariates and
		genetic parameters related to selection strategies and
		development of superior genotypes. It has two main
		functionalities, the first being about prediction models of
		covariates and environmental processes, while the second deals
		with the estimation of genetic parameters and selection
		strategies. Designed for researchers and professionals in
		genetics and environmental sciences, the package combines
		statistical methods for modeling and data analysis. This
		includes the plastochron estimate proposed by Porta et al.
		(2024) doi:10.1590/1807-1929/agriambi.v28n10e278299, Stress
		indices for genotype selection referenced by Ghazvini et al.
		(2024) doi:10.1007/s10343-024-00981-1, the Environmental Stress
		Index described by Tazzo et al. (2024)
		https://revistas.ufg.br/vet/article/view/77035, industrial
		quality indices of wheat genotypes (Szareski et al., 2019),
		doi:10.4238/gmr18223, Ear Indexes estimation (Rigotti et al.,
		2024), doi:10.13083/reveng.v32i1.17394, Selection index for
		protein and grain yield (de Pelegrin et al., 2017),
		doi:10.4236/ajps.2017.813224, Estimation of the ISGR - Genetic
		Selection Index for Resilience for environmental resilience
		(Bandeira et al., 2024)
		https://www.cropj.com/Carvalho_18_12_2024_825_830.pdf,
		estimation of Leaf Area Index (Meira et al., 2015) https://www.
		fag.edu.br/upload/revista/cultivando_o_saber/55d1ef202e494.pdf,
		Restriction of control variability (Carvalho et al., 2023)
		doi:10.4025/actasciagron.v45i1.56156, Risk of Disease
		Occurrence in Soybeans described by Engers et al. (2024)
		doi:10.1007/s40858-024-00649-1 and estimation of genetic
		parameters for selection based on balanced experiments (Yadav
		et al., 2024) doi:10.1155/2024/9946332.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
