<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		FDR Power // Computing Average and TPX Power under various BHFDR
		type sequential procedures. All of these procedures involve
		control of some summary of the distribution of the FDP, e.g.
		the proportion of discoveries which are false in a given
		experiment. The most widely known of these, the BH-FDR
		procedure, controls the FDR which is the mean of the FDP. A
		lesser known procedure, due to Lehmann and Romano, controls the
		FDX, or probability that the FDP exceeds a user provided
		threshold. This is less conservative than FWE control
		procedures but much more conservative than the BH-FDR
		proceudre. This package and the references supporting it
		introduce a new procedure for controlling the FDX which we call
		the BH-FDX procedure. This procedure iteratively identifies,
		given alpha and lower threshold delta, an alpha* less than
		alpha at which BH-FDR guarantees FDX control.  This uses
		asymptotic approximation and is only slightly more conservative
		than the BH-FDR procedure. Likewise, we can think of the power
		in multiple testing experiments in terms of a summary of the
		distribution of the True Positive Proportion (TPP), the portion
		of tests truly non-null distributed that are called
		significant. The package will compute power, sample size or any
		other missing parameter required for power defined as (i) the
		mean of the TPP (average power) or (ii) the probability that
		the TPP exceeds a given value, lambda, (TPX power) via
		asymptotic approximation. All supplied theoretical results are
		also obtainable via simulation. The suggested approach is to
		narrow in on a design via the theoretical approaches and then
		make final adjustments/verify the results by simulation. The
		theoretical results are described in Izmirlian, G (2020)
		Statistics and Probability letters,
		"doi:10.1016/j.spl.2020.108713", and an applied paper
		describing the methodology with a simulation study is in
		preparation. See citation("pwrFDR").
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
