<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Handle Ambiguity of Protein Identifications from Shotgun
		Proteomics // In shotgun proteomics, shared peptides (i.e.,
		peptides that might originate from different proteins sharing
		homology, from different proteoforms due to alternative mRNA
		splicing, post-translational modifications, proteolytic
		cleavages, and/or allelic variants) represent a major source of
		ambiguity in protein identifications. The 'net4pg' package
		allows to assess and handle ambiguity of protein
		identifications. It implements methods for two main
		applications. First, it allows to represent and quantify
		ambiguity of protein identifications by means of graph
		connected components (CCs). In graph theory, CCs are defined as
		the largest subgraphs in which any two vertices are connected
		to each other by a path and not connected to any other of the
		vertices in the supergraph. Here, proteins sharing one or more
		peptides are thus gathered in the same CC (multi-protein CC),
		while unambiguous protein identifications constitute CCs with a
		single protein vertex (single-protein CCs). Therefore, the
		proportion of single-protein CCs and the size of multi-protein
		CCs can be used to measure the level of ambiguity of protein
		identifications. The package implements a strategy to
		efficiently calculate graph connected components on large
		datasets and allows to visually inspect them. Secondly, the
		'net4pg' package allows to exploit the increasing availability
		of matched transcriptomic and proteomic datasets to reduce
		ambiguity of protein identifications. More precisely, it
		implement a transcriptome-based filtering strategy
		fundamentally consisting in the removal of those proteins whose
		corresponding transcript is not expressed in the sample-matched
		transcriptome. The underlying assumption is that, according to
		the central dogma of biology, there can be no proteins without
		the corresponding transcript. Most importantly, the package
		allows to visually inspect the effect of the filtering on
		protein identifications and quantify ambiguity before and after
		filtering by means of graph connected components. As such, it
		constitutes a reproducible and transparent method to exploit
		transcriptome information to enhance protein identifications.
		All methods implemented in the 'net4pg' package are fully
		described in Fancello and Burger (2022)
		doi:10.1186/s13059-022-02701-2.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
