<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Tools for Customer Lifetime Value Estimation // A set of state-
		of-the-art probabilistic modeling approaches to derive
		estimates of individual customer lifetime values (CLV).
		Commonly, probabilistic approaches focus on modelling 3
		processes, i.e. individuals' attrition, transaction, and
		spending process. Latent customer attrition models, which are
		also known as "buy-'til-you-die models", model the attrition as
		well as the transaction process. They are used to make
		inferences and predictions about transactional patterns of
		individual customers such as their future purchase behavior.
		Moreover, these models have also been used to predict
		individuals long-term engagement in activities such as playing
		an online game or posting to a social media platform. The
		spending process is usually modelled by a separate
		probabilistic model. Combining these results yields in lifetime
		values estimates for individual customers. This package
		includes fast and accurate implementations of various
		probabilistic models for non-contractual settings (e.g.,
		grocery purchases or hotel visits). All implementations support
		time-invariant covariates, which can be used to control for
		e.g., socio-demographics. If such an extension has been
		proposed in literature, we further provide the possibility to
		control for time-varying covariates to control for e.g.,
		seasonal patterns. Currently, the package includes the
		following latent attrition models to model individuals'
		attrition and transaction process: [1] Pareto/NBD model
		(Pareto/Negative-Binomial-Distribution), [2] the Extended
		Pareto/NBD model (Pareto/Negative-Binomial-Distribution with
		time-varying covariates), [3] the BG/NBD model (Beta-
		Gamma/Negative-Binomial-Distribution) and the [4] GGom/NBD
		(Gamma-Gompertz/Negative-Binomial-Distribution). Further, we
		provide an implementation of the Gamma/Gamma model to model the
		spending process of individuals.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
