<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Provides Batch Functions and Visualisation for Basic Statistical
		Procedures // Designed to streamline data analysis and
		statistical testing, reducing the length of R scripts while
		generating well-formatted outputs in 'pdf', 'Microsoft Word',
		and 'Microsoft Excel' formats. In essence, the package contains
		functions which are sophisticated wrappers around existing R
		functions that are called by using 'f_' (user f_riendly) prefix
		followed by the normal function name. This first version of the
		'rfriend' package focuses  primarily on data exploration,
		including tools for creating summary tables, f_summary(),
		performing data transformations, f_boxcox() in part based on
		'MASS/boxcox' and 'rcompanion', and f_bestNormalize() which
		wraps and extends functionality from the 'bestNormalize'
		package. Furthermore, 'rfriend' can automatically (or on
		request) generate visualizations such as boxplots, f_boxplot(),
		QQ-plots, f_qqnorm(), histograms f_hist(), and density plots.
		Additionally, the package includes four statistical test
		functions: f_aov(), f_kruskal_test(), f_glm(), f_chisq_test for
		sequential testing and visualisation of the 'stats' functions:
		aov(), kruskal.test(), glm() and chisq.test. These functions
		support testing multiple response variables and predictors,
		while also handling assumption checks, data transformations,
		and post hoc tests. Post hoc results are automatically
		summarized in a table using the compact letter display (cld)
		format for easy interpretation. The package also provides a
		function to do model comparison, f_model_comparison(), and
		several utility functions to simplify common R tasks. For
		example, f_clear() clears the workspace and restarts R with a
		single command; f_setwd() sets the working directory to match
		the directory of the current script; f_theme() quickly changes
		'RStudio' themes; and f_factors() converts multiple columns of
		a data frame to factors, and much more. If you encounter any
		issues or have feature requests, please feel free to contact me
		via email.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
