<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		An Euclidean View of Center and Spread // Illustrates the
		concepts developed in Sarkar and Rashid (2019, ISSN:0025-5742) 
		http://www.google.com/url?sa=trct=jq=esrc=ssource=webcd=cad=rja
		uact=8ved=2ahUKEwiH4deL3q3xAhWX73MBHR_wDaYQFnoECAUQAwurl=https%
		3A%2F%2Fwww.indianmathsociety.org.in%2Fmathstudent-
		part-2-2019.pdfusg=AOvVaw3SY--3T6UAWUnH5-Nj6bSc. This package
		helps a user guess four things (mean, MD, scaled MSD, and RMSD)
		before they get the SD. 1) The package displays the Empirical
		Cumulative Distribution Function (ECDF) of the given data. The
		user must choose the value of the mean by equating the areas of
		two colored (blue and green) regions. The package gives
		feedback to improve the choice until it is correct.
		Alternatively, the reader may continue with a different guess
		for the center (not necessarily the mean). 2) The user chooses
		the values of the Mean Deviation (MD) based on the ECDF of the
		deviations by equating the areas of two newly colored (blue and
		green) regions, with feedback from the package until the user
		guesses correctly. 3) The user chooses the Scaled Mean Squared
		Deviation (MSD) based on the ECDF of the scaled square
		deviations by equating the areas of two newly colored (blue and
		green) regions, with feedback from the package until the user
		guesses correctly. 4) The user chooses the Root Mean Squared
		Deviation (RMSD) by ensuring that its intersection with the
		ECDF of the deviations is at the same height as the
		intersection between the scaled MSD and the ECDF of the scaled
		squared deviations. Additionally, the intersection of two blue
		lines (the green dot) should fall on the vertical line at the
		maximum deviation. 5) Finally, if the mean is chosen correctly,
		only then the user can view the population SD (the same as the
		RMSD) and the sample SD (sqrt(n/(n-1))*RMSD) by clicking the
		respective buttons. If the mean is chosen incorrectly, the user
		is asked to correct it.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
