<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Simulation of Correlated Systems of Equations with Multiple
		Variable Types // Generate correlated systems of statistical
		equations which represent repeated measurements or clustered
		data.  These systems contain either: a) continuous normal, non-
		normal, and mixture variables based on the techniques of
		Headrick and Beasley (2004) DOI:10.1081/SAC-120028431 or b)
		continuous (normal, non-normal and mixture), ordinal, and count
		(regular or zero-inflated, Poisson and Negative Binomial)
		variables based on the hierarchical linear models (HLM)
		approach.  Headrick and Beasley's method for continuous
		variables calculates the beta (slope) coefficients based on the
		target correlations between independent variables and between
		outcomes and independent variables.  The package provides
		functions to calculate the expected correlations between
		outcomes, between outcomes and error terms, and between
		outcomes and independent variables, extending Headrick and
		Beasley's equations to include mixture variables.  These
		theoretical values can be compared to the simulated
		correlations.  The HLM approach requires specification of the
		beta coefficients, but permits group and subject-level
		independent variables, interactions among independent
		variables, and fixed and random effects, providing more
		flexibility in the system of equations.  Both methods permit
		simulation of data sets that mimic real-world clinical or
		genetic data sets (i.e. plasmodes, as in Vaughan et al., 2009,
		10.1016/j.csda.2008.02.032). The techniques extend those found
		in the 'SimMultiCorrData' and 'SimCorrMix' packages. Standard
		normal variables with an imposed intermediate correlation
		matrix are transformed to generate the desired distributions.
		Continuous variables are simulated using either Fleishman's
		third-order (DOI:10.1007/BF02293811) or Headrick's fifth-order
		(DOI:10.1016/S0167-9473(02)00072-5) power method transformation
		(PMT).  Simulation occurs at the component-level for continuous
		mixture distributions.  These components are transformed into
		the desired mixture variables using random multinomial
		variables based on the mixing probabilities.  The target
		correlation matrices are specified in terms of correlations
		with components of continuous mixture variables.  Binary and
		ordinal variables are simulated by discretizing the normal
		variables at quantiles defined by the marginal distributions.
		Count variables are simulated using the inverse CDF method.
		There are two simulation pathways for the multi-variable type
		systems which differ by intermediate correlations involving
		count variables.  Correlation Method 1 adapts Yahav and
		Shmueli's 2012 method DOI:10.1002/asmb.901 and performs best
		with large count variable means and positive correlations or
		small means and negative correlations.  Correlation Method 2
		adapts Barbiero and Ferrari's 2015 modification of the 'GenOrd'
		package DOI:10.1002/asmb.2072 and performs best under the
		opposite scenarios.  There are three methods available for
		correcting non-positive definite correlation matrices.  The
		optional error loop may be used to improve the accuracy of the
		final correlation matrices. The package also provides function
		to check parameter inputs and summarize the simulated systems
		of equations.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
