<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Genetic Association Studies // Some procedures including
		EIGENSTRAT (a procedure for detecting and correcting for
		population stratification through searching for the
		eigenvectors in genetic association studies), PCoC (a procedure
		for correcting for population stratification through
		calculating the principal coordinates and the clustering of the
		subjects), Tracy-Widom test (a procedure for detecting the
		significant eigenvalues of a matrix), distance regression (a
		procedure for detecting the association between a distance
		matrix and some independent variants of interest), single-
		marker test (a procedure for identifying the association
		between the genotype at a biallelic marker and a trait using
		the Wald test or the Fisher's exact test), MAX3 (a procedure
		for testing for the association between a single nucleotide
		polymorphism and a binary phenotype using the maximum value of
		the three test statistics derived for the recessive, additive,
		and dominant models), nonparametric trend test (a procedure for
		testing for the association between a genetic variant and a
		non-normal distributed quantitative trait based on the
		nonparametric risk), and nonparametric MAX3 (a procedure for
		testing for the association between a biallelic single
		nucleotide polymorphism and a quantitative trait using the
		maximum value of the three nonparametric trend tests derived
		for the recessive, additive, and dominant models), which are
		commonly used in genetic association studies. To cite this
		package in publications use: Lin Wang, Wei Zhang, and Qizhai
		Li. AssocTests: An R Package for Genetic Association Studies.
		Journal of Statistical Software. 2020; 94(5): 1-26.
		doi:10.18637/jss.v094.i05. (The DOI in the CITATION is for a
		new JSS publication that will be registered after publication
		on CRAN.)
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
