<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		A Compilation of Different Estimation Methods for Gravity Models
		// One can use gravity models to explain bilateral flows
		related to the sizes of bilateral partners, a measure of
		distance between them and other influences on interaction
		costs. The underlying idea is rather simple. The greater the
		masses of two bodies and the smaller the distance between them,
		the stronger they attract each other. This concept is applied
		to several research topics such as trade, migration or foreign
		direct investment. Even though the basic idea of gravity models
		is rather simple, they can become very complex when it comes to
		the choice of models or estimation methods. The package gravity
		targets to provide R users with the functions necessary to
		execute the most common estimation methods for gravity models,
		especially for cross-sectional data. It contains the functions
		Ordinary Least Squares (OLS), Fixed Effects, Double Demeaning
		(DDM), Bonus vetus OLS with simple averages (BVU) and with GDP-
		weights (BVW), Structural Iterated Least Squares (SILS),
		Tetrads as well as Poisson Pseudo Maximum Likelihood (PPML). By
		considering the descriptions of the estimation methods, users
		can see which method and data may be suited for a certain
		research question. In order to illustrate the estimation
		methods, this package includes a dataset called Gravity (see
		the description of the dataset for more information). On the
		Gravity Cookbook website
		(https://sites.google.com/site/hiegravity/) Keith Head and
		Thierry Mayer provide Stata code for the most common estimation
		methods for gravity models when using cross-sectional data. In
		order to get comparable results in R, the methods presented in
		the package gravity are designed to be consistent with this
		Stata code when choosing the option of robust variance
		estimation. However, compared to the Stata code available, the
		functions presented in this package provide users with more
		flexibility regarding the type of estimation (robust or not
		robust), the number and type of independent variables as well
		as the possible data. The functions all estimate gravity
		models, but they differ in whether they estimate them in their
		multiplicative or additive form, their requirements with
		respect to the data, their handling of Multilateral Resistance
		terms as well as their possibilities concerning the inclusion
		of unilateral independent variables. Therefore, they normally
		lead to different estimation results. We refer the user to the
		Gravity Cookbook website
		(https://sites.google.com/site/hiegravity/) for more
		information on gravity models in general. Head, K. and Mayer,
		T. (2014) DOI:10.1016/B978-0-444-54314-1.00003-3 provide a
		comprehensive and accessible overview of the theoretical and
		empirical development of the gravity literature as well as the
		use of gravity models and the various estimation methods,
		especially their merits and potential problems regarding
		applicability as well as different gravity datasets. All
		functions were tested to work on cross-sectional data and are
		consistent with the Stata code mentioned above. For the use
		with panel data no tests were performed. Therefore, it is up to
		the user to ensure that the functions can be applied to panel
		data. For a comprehensive overview of gravity models for panel
		data see Egger, P.,  Pfaffermayr, M. (2003)
		DOI:10.1007/s001810200146, Gomez-Herrera, E. (2013)
		DOI:10.1007/s00181-012-0576-2 and Head, K., Mayer, T.,  Ries,
		J. (2010) DOI:10.1016/j.jinteco.2010.01.002 as well as the
		references therein (see also the references included in the
		descriptions of the different functions). Depending on the
		panel dataset and the variables - specifically the type of
		fixed effects - included in the model, it may easily occur that
		the model is not computable. Also, note that by including
		bilateral fixed effects such as country-pair effects, the
		coefficients of time-invariant observables such as distance can
		no longer be estimated. Depending on the specific model, the
		code of the respective function may has to be changed in order
		to exclude the distance variable from the estimation. At the
		very least, the user should take special care with respect to
		the meaning of the estimated coefficients and variances as well
		as the decision about which effects to include in the
		estimation. As, to our knowledge at the moment, there is no
		explicit literature covering the estimation of a gravity
		equation by Double Demeaning, Structural Iterated Least Squares
		or Bonus Vetus OLS using panel data, we do not recommend to
		apply these methods in this case. Contributions, extensions and
		error corrections are very welcome. Please do not hesitate to
		contact us.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
