<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Consider Ambiguity in Probabilistic Descriptions Using Density
		Ratio Classes // Consider ambiguity in probabilistic
		descriptions by replacing a parametric probabilistic
		description of uncertainty by a non-parametric set of
		probability distributions in the form of a Density Ratio Class.
		This is of particular interest in Bayesian inference. The
		Density Ratio Class is particularly suited for this purpose as
		it is invariant under Bayesian inference, marginalization, and
		propagation through a deterministic model. Here, invariant
		means that the result of the operation applied to a Density
		Ratio Class is again a Density Ratio Class. In particular the
		invariance under Bayesian inference thus enables iterative
		learning within the same framework of Density Ratio Classes.
		The use of imprecise probabilities in general, and Density
		Ratio Classes in particular, lead to intervals of
		characteristics of probability distributions, such as
		cumulative distribution functions, quantiles, and means. The
		package is based on a sample of the distribution proportional
		to the upper bound of the class. Typically this will be a
		sample from the posterior in Bayesian inference. Based on such
		a sample, the package provides functions to calculate lower and
		upper class boundaries and lower and upper bounds of cumulative
		distribution functions, and quantiles. Rinderknecht, S.L.,
		Albert, C., Borsuk, M.E., Schuwirth, N., Kuensch, H.R. and
		Reichert, P. (2014) "The effect of ambiguous prior knowledge on
		Bayesian model parameter inference and prediction."
		Environmental Modelling  Software. 62, 300-315, 2014.
		doi:10.1016/j.envsoft.2014.08.020. Sriwastava, A. and Reichert,
		P. "Robust Bayesian Estimation of Value Function Parameters
		using Imprecise Priors." Submitted.
		https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=4973574.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
