<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Analysis of Korean National Forest Inventory Database //
		Understanding the current status of forest resources is
		essential for monitoring changes in forest ecosystems and
		generating related statistics. In South Korea, the National
		Forest Inventory (NFI) surveys over 4,500 sample plots
		nationwide every five years and records 70 items, including
		forest stand, forest resource, and forest vegetation surveys.
		Many researchers use NFI as the primary data for research, such
		as biomass estimation or analyzing the importance value of each
		species over time and space, depending on the research purpose.
		However, the large volume of accumulated forest survey data
		from across the country can make it challenging to manage and
		utilize such a vast dataset. To address this issue, we
		developed an R package that efficiently handles large-scale NFI
		data across time and space. The package offers a comprehensive
		workflow for NFI data analysis. It starts with data processing,
		where read_nfi() function reconstructs NFI data according to
		the researcher's needs while performing basic integrity checks
		for data quality.Following this, the package provides
		analytical tools that operate on the verified data. These
		include functions like summary_nfi() for summary statistics,
		diversity_nfi() for biodiversity analysis, iv_nfi() for
		calculating species importance value, and biomass_nfi() and
		cwd_biomass_nfi() for biomass estimation. Finally, for
		visualization, the tsvis_nfi() function generates graphs and
		maps, allowing users to visualize forest ecosystem changes
		across various spatial and temporal scales. This integrated
		approach and its specialized functions can enhance the
		efficiency of processing and analyzing NFI data, providing
		researchers with insights into forest ecosystems. The NFI Excel
		files (.xlsx) are not included in the R package and must be
		downloaded  separately. Users can access these NFI Excel files
		by visiting the Korea Forest Service Forestry Statistics
		Platform https://kfss.forest.go.kr/stat/ptl/article/articleList
		.do?curMenu=11694bbsId=microdataboard to download the annual
		NFI Excel files, which are bundled in .zip archives. Please
		note that this website is only available in Korean, and direct
		download links can be found in the notes section of the
		read_nfi() function.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
