<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Allows Specifying a Bivariate VAR (Vector Autoregression) with
		Desired Spectral Characteristics // The spectral
		characteristics of a bivariate series (Marginal Spectra,
		Coherency- and Phase-Spectrum) determine whether there is a
		strong presence of short-, medium-, or long-term fluctuations
		(components of certain frequencies in the spectral
		representation of the series) in each one of them.  These are
		induced by strong peaks of the marginal spectra of each series
		at the corresponding frequencies. The spectral characteristics
		also determine how strongly these short-, medium-, or long-term
		fluctuations of the two series are correlated between the two
		series. Information on this is provided by the Coherency
		spectrum at the corresponding frequencies. Finally, certain
		fluctuations of the two series may be lagged to each other.
		Information on this is provided by the Phase spectrum at the
		corresponding frequencies. The idea in this package is to
		define a VAR (Vector autoregression) model with desired
		spectral characteristics by specifying a number of polynomials,
		required to define the VAR. See Ioannidis(2007)
		doi:10.1016/j.jspi.2005.12.013. These are specified via their
		roots, instead of via their coefficients. This is an idea
		borrowed from the Time Series Library of R. Dahlhaus, where it
		is used for defining ARMA models for univariate time series.
		This way, one may e.g. specify a VAR inducing a strong presence
		of long-term fluctuations in series 1 and in series 2, which
		are weakly correlated, but lagged by a number of time units to
		each other, while short-term fluctuations in series 1 and in
		series 2, are strongly present only in one of the two series,
		while they are strongly correlated to each other between the
		two series. Simulation from such models allows studying the
		behavior of data-analysis tools, such as estimation of the
		spectra, under different circumstances, as e.g. peaks in the
		spectra, generating bias, induced by leakage.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
