<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Conditional Maximum Likelihood for Quadratic Exponential Models
		for Binary Panel Data // Estimation, based on conditional
		maximum likelihood, of the quadratic exponential model proposed
		by Bartolucci, F.  Nigro, V. (2010, Econometrica)
		DOI:10.3982/ECTA7531 and of a simplified and a modified version
		of this model. The quadratic exponential model is suitable for
		the analysis of binary longitudinal data when state dependence
		(further to the effect of the covariates and a time-fixed
		individual intercept) has to be taken into account. Therefore,
		this is an alternative to the dynamic logit model having the
		advantage of easily allowing conditional inference in order to
		eliminate the individual intercepts and then getting consistent
		estimates of the parameters of main interest (for the
		covariates and the lagged response). The simplified version of
		this model does not distinguish, as the original model does,
		between the last time occasion and the previous occasions. The
		modified version formulates in a different way the interaction
		terms and it may be used to test in a easy way state dependence
		as shown in Bartolucci, F., Nigro, V.  Pigini, C. (2018,
		Econometric Reviews) DOI:10.1080/07474938.2015.1060039. The
		package also includes estimation of the dynamic logit model by
		a pseudo conditional estimator based on the quadratic
		exponential model, as proposed by Bartolucci, F.  Nigro, V.
		(2012, Journal of Econometrics)
		DOI:10.1016/j.jeconom.2012.03.004. For large time dimensions of
		the panel, the computation of the proposed models involves a
		recursive function from Krailo M. D.,  Pike M. C. (1984,
		Journal of the Royal Statistical Society. Series C (Applied
		Statistics)) and Bartolucci F., Valentini, F.  Pigini C. (2021,
		Computational Economics DOI:10.1007/s10614-021-10218-2.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
