<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Analysis of Data with Measurement Error Using a Validation
		Subsample // Sometimes data for analysis are obtained using
		more convenient or less expensive means yielding "surrogate"
		variables for what could be obtained more accurately, albeit
		with less convenience; or less conveniently or at more expense
		yielding "reference" variables, thought of as being measured
		without error. Analysis of the surrogate variables measured
		with error generally yields biased estimates when the objective
		is to make inference about the reference variables. Often it is
		thought that ignoring the measurement error in surrogate
		variables only biases effects toward the null hypothesis, but
		this need not be the case. Measurement errors may bias
		parameter estimates either toward or away from the null
		hypothesis.    If one has a data set with surrogate variable
		data from the full sample, and also reference variable data
		from a randomly selected subsample, then one can assess the
		bias introduced by measurement error in parameter estimation,
		and use this information to derive improved estimates based
		upon all available data. Formulaically these estimates based
		upon the reference variables from the validation subsample
		combined with the surrogate variables from the whole sample can
		be interpreted as starting with the estimate from reference
		variables in the validation subsample, and "augmenting" this
		with additional information from the surrogate variables. This
		suggests the term "augmented" estimate.    The meerva package
		calculates these augmented estimates in the regression setting
		when there is a randomly selected subsample with both surrogate
		and reference variables. Measurement errors may be differential
		or non-differential, in any or all predictors (simultaneously)
		as well as outcome. The augmented estimates derive, in part,
		from the multivariate correlation between regression model
		parameter estimates from the reference variables and the
		surrogate variables, both from the validation subset. Because
		the validation subsample is chosen at random any biases imposed
		by measurement error, whether non-differential or differential,
		are reflected in this correlation and these correlations can be
		used to derive estimates for the reference variables using data
		from the whole sample.    The main functions in the package are
		meerva.fit which calculates estimates for a dataset, and
		meerva.sim.block which simulates multiple datasets as described
		by the user, and analyzes these datasets, storing the
		regression coefficient estimates for inspection.  The augmented
		estimates, as well as how measurement error may arise in
		practice, is described in more detail by Kremers WK (2021)
		arXiv:2106.14063 and is an extension of the works by Chen Y-H,
		Chen H. (2000) doi:10.1111/1467-9868.00243, Chen Y-H. (2002)
		doi:10.1111/1467-9868.00324, Wang X, Wang Q (2015)
		doi:10.1016/j.jmva.2015.05.017 and Tong J, Huang J, Chubak J,
		et al. (2020) doi:10.1093/jamia/ocz180.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
