<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		FROC Analysis by Bayesian Approaches // Execute
		BayesianFROC::fit_GUI_Shiny() (or fit_GUI_Shiny_MRMC()) for a
		graphical user interface via Shiny. The free-response receiver
		operating characteristic (FROC) method is a generalization of
		receiver operating characteristic (ROC) analysis. However,
		Chakraborty's classical model is non-generative in the sense
		that it cannot synthesize data. This package aims to modify his
		models to be generative using a Bayesian approach, and to
		verify that our models fit practical datasets. In signal
		detection theory, the number of true positives never exceeds
		the number of targets. However, this is not explained by any
		existing model. Thus, in this package, the author contributes
		to FROC theory by refining Chakrabortys model to obtain models
		that are generative. This modification allows us to use FROC
		analysis in a general statistical scheme, and as a benefit, our
		generative model can be applied to calculations of posterior
		predictive p values that require generation of synthetic
		datasets from fitted models. Furthermore, this package presents
		new models for comparison of modalities. Modality comparison is
		a common problem in radiology, and has been studied
		extensively. However, in many medical studies, such problems
		are addressed with non-Bayesian methods such as ANOVA. As a
		supplementary topic, this work presents a Bayesian model that
		includes individual differences. With this model, we can
		account for differences between individual readers when
		comparing modalities, using Bayesian rather than ML-methods.
		The author found the existing FROC model in [1] to be non-
		generative for calculation of  posterior predictive p values.
		Replacing the ML-based method with a Bayesian approach differs
		from standard practice but provides insight into the problems
		of existing methods. Please execute the following R scripts
		from the R (R studio) console, demo(demo_MRMC, package =
		"BayesianFROC"); demo(demo_srsc, package = "BayesianFROC");
		demo(demo_stan, package = "BayesianFROC");
		demo(demo_drawcurves_srsc, package = "BayesianFROC");
		demo_Bayesian_FROC(); demo_Bayesian_FROC_without_pause().
		References: [1] Dev Chakraborty (1989) doi:10.1118/1.596358
		Maximum likelihood analysis of free - response receiver
		operating characteristic (FROC) data. Pre-print: Issei Tsunoda;
		Generative Models for free-response receiver operating
		characteristic analysis. See the vignettes for more details.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
