<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		FROC Analysis by Bayesian Approaches // For details please see
		vignettes in this package. This package aims to provide new
		methods for the so-called Free-response Receiver Operating
		Characteristic (FROC) analysis. The ultimate aim of FROC
		analysis is to compare observer performances, which means
		comparing characteristics, such as area under the curve (AUC)
		or figure of merit (FOM). In this package, we only use the
		notion of AUC for modality comparison. In the radiological FROC
		context, by a word modality we mean imaging methods such as
		Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI), Computed Tomography
		(CT),Positron Emission Tomography (PET). So there is a problem
		that which imaging method is better to detect the lesions from
		shadows in radiographs. To solve the modality comparison
		issues, this package provides the new methods using
		hierarchical Bayesian models proposed by the author of this
		package. Using this package, one can obtain at least one
		conclusion that which imaging methods are better for finding
		lesions in radiographs with the case of your data. Fitting FROC
		statistical models is sometimes not so good, it can easily
		confirm by drawing FROC curves and comparing the curves and the
		points constructed by False Positive fractions (FPFs) and True
		Positive Fractions (TPFs), we can validate the goodness of fit
		intuitively. Such validation is also implemented by the Chi
		square goodness of fit statistics in the Bayesian context in
		which the parameter is not deterministic, thus by integrating
		it with the posterior predictive measure, we get a desired
		value. To compare each imaging methods, i.e., modalities,  we
		evaluate the AUC for each modality which gives us a comparison
		of modalities. FROC is developed by Dev Chakraborty, his FROC
		model in 1989 paper relies on the maximal likelihood
		methodology. In this package, I modified and provided the
		alternative Bayesian FROC model. Strictly speaking, his model
		does not coincide with models in this package. I hope that
		medical researchers use not only the frequentist method but
		also alternative Bayesian methods. In medical research, many
		problems are considered under only frequentist methods, such as
		the notion of p-values. But p-value is sometimes misunderstood.
		Bayesian methods provide very simple, direct, intuitive answer
		for research questions. To know how to use this package, please
		execute the following codes from the R (R studio) console,
		demo(demo_MRMC,package="BayesianFROC"); demo(demo_srsc,
		package="BayesianFROC"); demo(demo_stan, package =
		"BayesianFROC"); demo(demo_drawcurves_srsc,
		package="BayesianFROC"); demo_Bayesian_FROC(). References: Dev
		Chakraborty (1989) doi:10.1118/1.596358 Maximum likelihood
		analysis of free - response receiver operating characteristic
		(FROC) data. Pre-print: Issei Tsunoda; Bayesian Models for
		free-response receiver operating characteristic analysis.
		Combining frequentist methods with Bayesian methods, we can
		obtain more reliable answer for research questions.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
