<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Elemental Descriptive and Inferential Statistics // Provides
		tools to teach students elemental statistics. The main topics
		covered are descriptive statistics, probability models
		(discrete and continuous variables) and statistical inference
		(confidence intervals and hypothesis tests). One of the main
		advantages of this package is that allows the user to read
		quite a variety of types of data files with one unique command.
		Moreover it includes shortcuts to simple but up-to-now not in R
		descriptive features such a complete frequency table or an
		histogram with the optimal number of intervals. Related to
		model distributions (both discrete and continuous), the package
		allows the student to easy plot the mass/density function,
		distribution function and quantile function just detailing as
		input arguments the known population parameters. The inference
		related tools are basically confidence interval and hypothesis
		testing. Having defined independent commands for these two
		tools makes it easier for the student to understand what the
		software is performing, and it also helps the student to have a
		better knowledge on which specific tool they need to use in
		each situation. Moreover, the hypothesis testing commands
		provide not only the numeric result on the screen but also a
		very intuitive graph (which includes the statistic
		distribution, the observed value of the statistic, the
		rejection area and the p-value) that is very useful for the
		student to visualise the process. The regression section
		includes up to now, a simple linear model, with one single
		command the student can obtain the numeric summary as well as
		the corresponding diagram with the adjusted regression model
		and a legend with basic information (formula of the adjusted
		model and R-squared).
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
