<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Topologically Correct Isosurface Extraction // Isosurfaces
		extraction algorithms are a powerful tool in the interpretation
		of volumetric data. The isosurfaces play an important role in
		several scientific fields, such as biology, medicine, chemistry
		and computational fluid dynamics. And, for the data to be
		correctly interpreted, it is crucial that the isosurface be
		correctly represented. The Marching Cubes algorithm, proposed
		by Lorensen and Cline doi:10.1145/37401.37422 in 1987, is
		clearly one of the most popular isosurface extraction
		algorithms, and an important tool for many visualization
		specialists and researchers. The generalized adoption of the
		Marching Cubes has resulted in many improvements in its
		algorithm, including, the establishment of the topological
		correctness of the generated mesh. In 2013, Custodio et al.
		doi:10.1016/j.cag.2013.04.004 noted and corrected algorithmic
		inaccuracies that compromised the topological correctness of
		the mesh generated by the last version of the Marching Cubes
		Algorithm: the Marching Cubes 33 proposed by Chernyaev in 1995,
		implemented in 2003 by Lewiner et al.
		doi:10.1080/10867651.2003.10487582. In 2019, Custodio et al.
		(in the work An Extended Triangulation to the Marching Cubes 33
		Algorithm) proposed an extended triangulation to the Marching
		Cubes 33 algorithm, in the proposed algorithm the grid vertex
		are labeled with "+", "-" and "=", according to the
		relationship between its scalar field value and the
		isovalue.The inclusion of the "=" grid vertex label naturally
		avoids degenerate triangles, a well-known issue in meshes
		generated by the Marching Cubes. The Marching Cubes algorithm
		has been implemented using many software programs and
		compilers: C++, proposed by Lewiner et al. (2003); 'MATLAB',
		proposed by Hammer (2011); and R, proposed by Feng and Tierney
		(2008). Marching Cubes is also integrated into many
		visualization toolkits. The complexity of an algorithm
		increases considerably when it aims to reproduce the topology
		of the trilinear interpolant correctly. This complexity can
		sometimes result in errors in the algorithm or in its
		implementation. During our experiments we observe that all the
		implementations mentioned have critical issues that compromise
		the continuity and the topological correctness of the generated
		mesh. The 'tcie' package is a toolkit with a topologically
		correct implementation of the Marching Cubes algorithm, based
		on the Custodio et al. work, which implements the most recent
		improvements of the algorithm.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
