<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Simulation and Group Sequential Monitoring of Randomized Two-
		Stage Treatment Efficacy Trials with Time-to-Event Endpoints //
		A modification of the preventive vaccine efficacy trial design
		of Gilbert, Grove et al. (2011, Statistical Communications in
		Infectious Diseases) is implemented, with application generally
		to individual-randomized clinical trials with multiple active
		treatment groups and a shared control group, and a study
		endpoint that is a time-to-event endpoint subject to right-
		censoring. The design accounts for the issues that the efficacy
		of the treatment/vaccine groups may take time to accrue while
		the multiple treatment administrations/vaccinations are given;
		there is interest in assessing the durability of treatment
		efficacy over time; and group sequential monitoring of each
		treatment group for potential harm, non-efficacy/efficacy
		futility, and high efficacy is warranted. The design divides
		the trial into two stages of time periods, where each treatment
		is first evaluated for efficacy in the first stage of follow-
		up, and, if and only if it shows significant treatment efficacy
		in stage one, it is evaluated for longer-term durability of
		efficacy in stage two. The package produces plots and tables
		describing operating characteristics of a specified design
		including an unconditional power for intention-to-treat and
		per-protocol/as-treated analyses; trial duration; probabilities
		of the different possible trial monitoring outcomes (e.g.,
		stopping early for non-efficacy); unconditional power for
		comparing treatment efficacies; and distributions of numbers of
		endpoint events occurring after the treatments/vaccinations are
		given, useful as input parameters for the design of studies of
		the association of biomarkers with a clinical outcome
		(surrogate endpoint problem). The code can be used for a single
		active treatment versus control design and for a single-stage
		design.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
