<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Sequence Analysis // Provides: 1) By Giving UniProtKB, the
		Protein Sequence will be returned from UniProt database. 2)By
		Giving UniProtKB, the Nucleotide Sequence will be returned from
		EBI database. 3) Amino acid Composition is calculated by four
		different methods: a) Twenty-two independent categories are
		considered, with one amino acid for each category. B) Five
		categories (Nonpolar Aliphatic, Nonpolar Aromatic, Polar
		Uncharged, Polar Positively Charged, Polar Negatively Charged)
		are considered according to the standard chemical structures of
		amino acids. c) Six categories (Nonpolar Aliphatic, Nonpolar
		Aromatic, Polar Uncharged, Polar Positively Charged, Polar
		Negatively Charged, Special cases) are considered which
		Cysteine, Selenocysteine, Glycine and Proline are placed in
		Special cases group. d)Eight categories are clustered via
		k-means algorithm on Physicochemical index of amino acids. 4)
		GC Content: Percentage of nucleotide g and c in sequence. 5)
		Codon usage: Frequency of occurrence of synonymous codons. 6)
		Stacking Energy: The NN model for nucleic acids assumes that
		the stability of a given base pair depends on the identity and
		orientation of neighboring base pairs. Stacking Energy =
		DeltaG(total) = Sigma (n(i)*DeltaG(i)) + DeltaG(init) +
		DeltaG(end) + DeltaG(sym), which DeltaG for i, init and end is
		obtained by Unified NN free energy parameter. Symmetry of self-
		complementary duplexes is also included by DeltaG(sym) equals
		to +0.43 (kcal/mol) if the duplex is self-complementary and
		zero if it is non-self-complementary. 7) Complement of desired
		nucleotide sequence. 8) Reverse of desired nucleotide sequence.
		9) Reverse-Complement of desired nucleotide sequence. 10)
		Protein, Gene and Organism of desired UniProt ID. 11)
		Converting nucleotide sequence to protein sequence. 12) Getting
		Localization From Gene Ontology Cellular Component inside
		Uniprot. 13) All related codons of desired amino acid.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
