<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Expanding Ploidy and Allele-Frequency on Nested Subpopulations //
		Expanding Ploidy and Allele Frequency on Nested Subpopulations
		(expands) characterizes coexisting subpopulations in a single
		tumor sample using copy number and allele frequencies derived
		from exome- or whole genome sequencing input data
		(http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24177718). The model
		detects coexisting genotypes by leveraging run-specific
		tradeoffs between depth of coverage and breadth of coverage.
		This package predicts the number of clonal expansions, the size
		of the resulting subpopulations in the tumor bulk, the
		mutations specific to each subpopulation, tumor purity and
		phylogeny. The main function runExPANdS() provides the complete
		functionality needed to predict coexisting subpopulations from
		single nucleotide variations (SNVs) and associated copy
		numbers.  The robustness of subpopulation predictions increases
		with the number of mutations provided. It is recommended that
		at least 200 mutations are used as input to obtain stable
		results. Updates in version 1.7 include: (1) Higher
		subpopulation detection specificity, in particular for small
		subpopulations. (2) Higher accuracy for mutation assignment to
		subpopulations. (3) Whenever possible, SNVs are assigned not
		only to the subpopulation in which they first occurred, but
		also to descending subpopulations. (4) Two additional output
		files are created: subpopulation specific ploidy matrix and a
		summary file of all detected subpopulations, including
		information on the inferred ancestor and the closest descendant
		of each subpopulation. (5) New subpopulation plotting options
		(function plotSPs). (6) New phylogeny plotting option: user can
		choose between consensus and germline population to be included
		as control. (7) 50 simulated samples of various genetic
		complexities and measurement precision included for user
		testing. Special thanks to Dr. Ryan Morin for his contributions
		that have led to higher accuracy measures during simulations
		for mutation assignment to subpopulations, as well as advanced
		visualization features of assigned mutations. Further
		documentation and FAQ available at http://dna-
		discovery.stanford.edu/software/expands.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
