<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Expanding Ploidy and Allele-Frequency on Nested Subpopulations //
		Expanding Ploidy and Allele Frequency on Nested Subpopulations
		(expands) characterizes coexisting subpopulations in a single
		tumor sample using copy number and allele frequencies derived
		from exome- or whole genome sequencing input data
		(http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24177718). The model
		detects coexisting genotypes by leveraging run-specific
		tradeoffs between depth of coverage and breadth of coverage.
		This package predicts the number of clonal expansions, the size
		of the resulting subpopulations in the tumor bulk, the
		mutations specific to each subpopulation and tumor purity. The
		main function runExPANdS() provides the complete functionality
		needed to predict coexisting subpopulations from single
		nucleotide variations (SNVs) and associated copy numbers.  The
		robustness of subpopulation predictions increases with the
		number of mutations provided. It is recommended that at least
		200 mutations are used as input to obtain stable results.
		Updates in version 1.6 include: (1) So far mutations had been
		assigned to maximal one subpopulation. However mutations may
		not be exclusive to the assigned subpopulation but may also be
		present in smaller, descending subpopulations. Whether or not
		this is the case is now decided by leveraging the predicted
		phylogenetic structure of the subpopulation composition. (2)
		Included homozygous deletion as potential scenario when
		modeling (SNV,CNV) pairs with overlapping genomic location,
		that are propagated during distinct clonal expansions. (3)
		Optimized solution to improve sensitivity at cell-frequency
		distribution margins. Need for improvement was because
		subpopulation detection sensitivity correlates to centrality of
		subpopulation size during clustering. Tolerance of copy number
		and allele frequency measurement errors must be higher for
		marginal cell-frequencies than for central cell-frequencies, in
		order to counteract the reduced cluster detection sensitivity
		at the cell-frequency distribution margins. This is only
		relevant during subpopulation detection (SNV clustering), cell-
		frequency independent error tolerance still applies during SNV
		assignment. (4) Fixed a bug where incorrect data matrix
		conversion could occur when handing non-numerical matrix as
		parameter to function runExPANdS(). Further documentation and
		FAQ around this package is available at http://dna-
		discovery.stanford.edu/software/expands.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
