<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Multivariate Genome Wide Marginal Epistasis Test // Epistasis,
		commonly defined as the interaction between genetic loci, is
		known to play an important role in the phenotypic variation of
		complex traits. As a result, many statistical methods have been
		developed to identify genetic variants that are involved in
		epistasis, and nearly all of these approaches carry out this
		task by focusing on analyzing one trait at a time. Previous
		studies have shown that jointly modeling multiple phenotypes
		can often dramatically increase statistical power for
		association mapping. In this  package, we present the
		'multivariate MArginal ePIstasis Test' ('mvMAPIT')  a multi-
		outcome generalization of a recently proposed epistatic
		detection method which seeks to detect marginal epistasis or
		the combined pairwise interaction effects between a given
		variant and all other variants. By searching for marginal
		epistatic effects, one can identify genetic variants that are
		involved in epistasis without the need to identify the exact
		partners with which the variants interact  thus, potentially
		alleviating much of the statistical and computational burden
		associated with conventional explicit search based methods. Our
		proposed 'mvMAPIT' builds upon this strategy by taking
		advantage of correlation structure between traits to improve
		the identification of variants involved in epistasis. We
		formulate 'mvMAPIT' as a  multivariate linear mixed model and
		develop a multi-trait variance component estimation algorithm
		for efficient parameter inference and P-value computation.
		Together with reasonable model approximations, our proposed
		approach is scalable to moderately sized genome-wide
		association studies. Crawford et al. (2017)
		doi:10.1371/journal.pgen.1006869. Stamp et al. (2023)
		doi:10.1093/g3journal/jkad118.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
