<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription>
		Psychometric Networks for Intensive Longitudinal Data // In the
		past decade, mental processes have been conceptualized as
		complex networks of interacting psychiatric symptoms. These
		networks that can be visualized by means of conditional
		independence graphs. For estimating the underlying directed
		graph from intensive longitudinal data, vector autoregression
		(VAR) is the most commonly used tool. This package wraps
		several methods in the VAR family that can be used to estimate
		conditional independence graphs (networks) from multivariate
		time-series data. The package can fit the simple VAR and VARX
		model Lutkepohl, H. (2005) doi:10.1007/978-3-540-27752-1 that
		are currently available from the R package 'vars', and its
		sparse alternative by Basu S. and Michailidis, G.(2015)
		doi:10.1214/15-AOS1315 and sparse VECM implemented in the R
		package 'sparsevar'. The sparse graphical VAR with covariance
		estimation by Wild, B., Eichler, M., Friederich, H. C.,
		Hartmann, M., Zipfel, S.,  Herzog, W. (2010)
		doi:10.1186/1471-2288-10-28 from the R package 'graphicalVAR'
		and the dynamic factor model by Doz, Gianone  Reichlin (2011)
		doi:10.1016/j.jeconom.2011.02.012 from the R package
		'dynfactoR' are also available. Sparse estimation of high
		dimensional VAR, VARMA and VARX models using hierarchical lag
		structures Nicholson, W. B., Bien, J., Matteson, D. S. (2017)
		arXiv:1412.5250v3 implemented in the R package 'bigtime' and
		mixed VAR for symptom time series with marginal distributions
		in the exponential family Haslbeck, J., Waldorp, L. J. (2015)
		arXiv:1510.06871 from the package 'mgm' can also be used with
		this package. For the inference of symptom networks from
		multivariate time series of multiple individuals the 'psychNET'
		package adopts the multi-level VAR by Epskamp, S., Waldorp, L.
		J., Mottus, R.,  Borsboom, D. (2017) arXiv:1609.04156v6
		implemented in the R package 'mlVAR' and for the high-
		dimensional setting the sparse time series chain graphical
		(group graphical VAR) model by Abegaz, F., Wit, E. (2013)
		doi:10.1093/biostatistics/kxt005 available from the R package
		'sparseTSCGM'.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
